Unekwu Noel Abdullahi

in https://www.linkedin.com/in/noelabdullahi/

PROFILE

Noel is a Data Scientist and Artificial Intelligence product owner. He currently supports multiple projects as an Executive product leader at Data science Network Nigeria.

He has more than 20 years of experience of drawing insights from very large data sets as an Earth scientist, Stress modeler and Wellsite Geologist at Chevron corporation.

EDUCATION

Data Analyst

MasterSchool Newyork, United States

Masterschool offers virtual training courses for gifted learners to become data analysts. With over 650 hours of immersive practice, students learn Python, SQL, Tableau, and A/B Testing and other important skills.

Mini MBA 11/2021 - 05/2022 Tekedia Institue

Tekedia Mini-MBA, is an innovation management program, optimized for business execution and growth, with digital operational overlay.

Competing in the Age of AI

Harvard Business School Executive Education

The adoption of artificial intelligence is causing a revolutionary transformation in businesses across all industries. This program provides a comprehensive digital strategy to smoothly transition organizations towards an AI-based business model, fully unlocking the potential for growth through AI.

Masters in Applied Geophysics

University of lagos

https://www.credly.com/badges/1d980319-8c79-4ada-81ac-1c3729f3fb99/public_url

11/2009 - 03/2012 Lagos, Nigeria

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

Lead Consultant

Issachar concepts Incorporated

- Created 4 oil and gas solutions that improved well planning efficiency by 20%, saving over \$1,000,000.
- Led DSN's SpotOn team, placing in the top 94 teams in the 2021 Cisco Global Problem Solver Challenge.
- Developed training resources for data analysis, automation, and machine learning algorithms in the oil and gas industry.

Earth Scientist 08/2002 - 08/2021

Chevron Corporation

- 15+ years in various roles as wellsite geologist, log analyst, and contract administrator gathering, evaluating, and deriving insights from big data, which resulted in a \$24 million cost savings in GNPT for the 2016/2017 Cheetah drilling campaign.
- Reduce contract processing time by 50% through automation and simplification of the contract tracking spreadsheet, thereby reducing out-of-contract spend by >\$250,000.
- led Team Diamond in building a low code automated project management solution for managers and project teams. This solution was designed to improve project delivery time by 20%, leading to a cost avoidance in excess of \$200,000 due to quick and timely decisions by project owners and timely execution of projects in the first Applied Research and Technological Services digital hackathon in 2019.

10/2022 - 10/2023

Boston, United States

09/2021 - 11/2021 Boston, United States

11/2021 - present

Houston, Texas

SKILLS

- A/B Testing · Consulting · Business Intelligence (BI) · Extract, Transform, Load (ETL) · Project Coordination · Financial Forecasting · Product Development · SQL · Python (Programming Language) · Organizational Leadership · Machine Learning · Strategy · Supervisory Skills
- Petroleum Engineering · Data Management · Extract, Transform, Load (ETL) · Drilling Engineering · Data Governance · Project Coordination · Lean Six Sigma · Machine Learning · Supervisory Skills · Geophysics · Wellsite Geologist

PUBLICATIONS

https://nape.org.ng/wp-content/uploads/2020/09/18-27.-Formation-Related-Drilling-Difficulty.pdf

19/11/2020

Nigerian Association Of Petroleum Explorationist

The Deep Water 02 well received a detailed investigation after incurring \$20M of non-productive time. The report analyzed the reasons for the NPT and suggested best practices for future wells.

Coring Unconsolidated Formations under Challenging Drilling Conditions – A Case Study, Swamp- Niger Delta.

06/08/2018

https://www.researchgate.net/publication/328166990_Coring_Unconsolidated_Formations_under_C hallenging_Drilling_Conditions_-_A_Case_Study_Swamp-_Niger_Delta
The paper describes an innovative approach to mitigate challenging drilling conditions in

The paper describes an innovative approach to mitigate challenging drilling condition order to achieve a high recovery factor (93%) of high-quality cores. T

AWARDS

Reservoir Management Excellence Award

2017

Chevron

For setting gold standards in geologic non-productive time tracking and developing a plan of action that resulted in a \$24 million cost savings

Diversity Day Essay Writting Competition(First Runner up)

Chevron

Chevron values Diversity and Inclusion and holds events like essay contests to celebrate it.

MASTERSCHOOL PORTFOLIO

https://drive.google.com/file/d/1 IwVWNN9Tf7mDmhhZZpkOx2OJgLiQq3Um/viewhttps://drive.google.com/file/d/1 IwVWNN9Tf7mDmhhATQpur/viewhttps://drive.google.com/file/d/1 IwVWNN9Tf7mDmhATQpur/viewhttps://drive.google.com/file/d/1 IwVWNN9Tf7mDmhATQpur/viewhttps://drive.google.com/file/d/1 IwVWNN9Tf7mDmhATQpur/viewhttps://drive.google.com/file/d/

Built Financial And Sales Model Forecast With Excel Using NYSE Kaggle Data Sets

https://drive.google.com/file/d/1Bm3FESz1eAjNyJ7xUikAmUqVSn8ociKg/view

Deforestation Exploration project

https://drive.google.com/file/d/1wL2hCKcOIk9TRTtCjVm9EM1MfwYq6YaA/view

Tableau Visualization of the U.S Census Data sets

PROFFESIONAL MEMBERSHIP

Society of Petroleum Engineers

Nigerian Association Of Petroleum Explorationist

ORGANIZATIONS

Chevron Corporation

01/2018 - 08/2021

XYZ Network Community Engagement Champion

Organized career mentoring for over 150 students in the local public schools and helped raise over \$2000 to support orphanages.